Garrett Hudson

garrett.hudson46@gmail.com | (919) 606-6599 | Raleigh, NC 27587

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/garretthudson46 | GitHub: github.com/ghudson46 | Portfolio: www.garretthudson.com

Summary

I am a full-stack web developer with a vast array of knowledge in front end and back end languages, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices. My past career as professional football player taught me to work hard, manage my time, communicate and collaborate with a team, and never give up until you have achieved your goal . I received a post graduate certificate from UNC Chapel Hill's full stack coding bootcamp and have been working as a free lance developer since March 2020. In addition to my coursework at UNC, I have also received certificates for JavaScript, python from Codecademy.

Experience

Front-End Web Developer

Freelance [March 2020– Present]

- Have helped several individuals and small business with the user interface and user experience of their websites.
- Have refactored existing code to optimize websites for SEO and accessibility.

•

Social Media Manager

Heritage Payment Solutions [December 2019–Present]

- Responsible for content creation, posting, and maintaining the company's Instagram, twitter, and Facebook accounts
- Create google ads to allow us to generate leads
- Use google analytics to observe the effectiveness of the company's website and digital marketing campaigns

Assistant Project Manager

Capitol City Homes [July 2019-December 2019]

- Responsible for the coordination and supervision of residential construction
- Managed schedule from permit to closing, scheduled vendors and subcontractors, met with inspectors, and oriented buyers with their new home

Professional Football Player (Tight End)

New York Jets, Detroit Lions, Washington Redskins, Atlanta Legends (AAF), New York Guardians (XFL) [April 2018 – February 2020]

- Played 3 professional seasons in the NFL, XFL, and AAF
- Appeared in 4 games for the Washington Redskins in 2018, making 1 catch vs the Baltimore Ravens
- Retired in February 2020 after a career ending wrist injury

Education

University of North Carolina [June 2020 – December 2020]

- Coding Bootcamp in full-stack web development
- Will graduate from the program in December 2020 and be fully certified as a full-stack web developer

University of Richmond [January 2015 - December 2017]

- Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (Marketing)
- 3.01 GPA

University of North Carolina [June 2013 – December 2014]

- Pre-business
- Transferred to Richmond to pursue football

Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- BootStrap
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Node.js
- Express.js
- Python
- mySQL
- Git Bash/Terminal

Projects

- Pawsibilities https://cptspooky.github.io/Pawsibility/
 - Pawsibilities is a web application designed to search for pets that need a home, and give the user their information and location so they can be adopted.
 - This project was worked on as a group. We used HTML, CSS, bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery, as well as pet finder API and map box API.
 - I was responsible for writing the script for the search form, storing input in the local storage, and generating the map, marker and popup to show the animal's location.
- RateFlix https://ghudson46.github.io/rateflix
 - I created rateflix as a personal application to get quick information on various movies. I used ajax to call the omdd api and render html to give me the title, movie poster, release year, director, cast, run time, and rotten tomatoes score.
 - For this project I used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and OMDB api.
- Weather Dashboard https://ghudson46.github.io/weather-forecast/
 - This weather dashboard is a web application designed to take a city, inputted by the user, and show the current weather in that

city. The dashboard also shows the user the forecast over the next 5 days for that city, Cities are saved in local storage after they

are searched, and can be easily clicked in the future to quickly bring up weather data.

- For this project I used HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, and the open weather API
- Star Wars Quiz https://ghudson46.github.io/code-quiz-HW4/
 - This project is a web application that runs a quiz-style game. The user is asked questions about the Star Wars universe. The use has 60 seconds to answer as many questions as possible. Each correct answer is worth 1 point and each wrong answer deducts 5 seconds from the timer. When the game is over, the user can save their high score into local storage before playing again and trying to improve on their score.
 - o For this project I used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Iron-Man mobile game https://ghudson46.github.io/iron-mans-flight/
 - This project was something I did for fun. It is a web application that was designed for play on a smart phone or tablet. The user guides iron man through a field of obstacles in front of the NYC skyline. The user gets a point for each obstacle passed and the game ends when the user steers the game character into an obstacle. I took inspiration from the game flappy bird. (This game does not work on a desktop unless the screen has touch capabilities)
 - o For this game I used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I also used photoshop to create a sprite sheet for the game character, background, obstacles, logos, and scoreboard.

Awards and Achievements

Academic

 Selected to the CAA academic all-conference team in 2016 and 2017

Athletic

- 1st team All-CAA Tight End in 2016 and 2017
- Pre-season All-American in 2017
- Set University of Richmond single-season and career records for receiving yards and touchdowns by a Tight End
- Selected to play in the NFLPA Collegiate Bowl in 2017